字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：长颈鹿  盐湖凉开水  Elena
翻译：菊酱御用铲屎官  秋乙一
翻译：胖达萌萌哒  赫力场和姚老师 木浅
校对：持久君
后期：8T     总监：somehacker  持久君
就位后请答复  戴维斯中士
Acknowledge when in position, Sergeant Davis.
D组1队已收到  信号一直不好
Dagger team 1, copy. I keep losing you.
增援什么时候到达
How long till my backup's here?
正在查询  请待命
Working on it. Stand by.
八至十分钟后到达  建议你留在原地
Say eight to ten minutes. Advise you stay put.
我等不及了
I can't wait for backup.
让他们随后进来
Send them in behind me.
戴维斯  留在原地  他们正在赶来
Davis, maintain your position. They're on their way.
这里是D组1队  你们看到了吗
Dagger team 1, are you seeing this?
这里有东西在干扰信号
There's some kind of disturbance here.
戴维斯  什么东西  你看到什么了
Davis, what is that? What are you seeing?
见鬼
What the hell?
戴维斯
Davis.
戴维斯  汇报情况
Davis, what's your status?
戴维斯  请回话
Davis, come in!
幽   冥
找到你了
Got you.
可能会推迟
Gonna get a late start.
这是一次秘密会议
Right, well, it's a closed session.
规则大部分都没变...
Most of the specs stayed the same...
奥斯本博士请致电204室
Dr. Osbourne, call 204. Dr. Osbourne, call 204.
据我所知  他们正为那项研发申请临时许可
They're issuing temporaries for that R and D, as far as I know.
这也是基地防空地面警备系统的一部分吗
Is that part of the same BADGE or...?
肯定是
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
-好吧  -进行得怎样了
- All right. - How's it going?
-我们会成功的  -马蒂已经到了吗
- We'll get everything. - Marty was already in?
-是的  -她还在做那个项目吗
- Yeah. - And she's working on that project?
他们大概一周内能完成  我想说...
They'll be done in about a week. I was gonna say...
唐·泰勒  请到B栋激光实验室报到
Don Taylor, report to laser laboratory building B, laser lab.
我会看一下的
Okay, I'll take a look.
-你去哪了  -解决点问题
- Where have you been? - Solving problems.
你身上都是灰
You look... dusty.
有时候脏点是无法避免的  埃弗雷姆
Sometimes you gotta get dusty, Efrem.
-要检测脉冲吗  -是的
- Test the pulse? - Yeah.
我去地下室问约翰逊要点并四苯来着
Went down to the vault, asked Johnson for some tetracene,
但貌似我们并没有库存
but apparently, we don't store it.
那东西都过时了  而且还贵得要命
It's outdated and expensive as shit.
只是后来贵了  九十年代的时候很便宜
It got expensive. Back in the '90s, it used to be cheap.
所以如果认真找找的话...
So, if you look hard enough...
还是能找到些的
You can still find some lying around.
你找街头匪帮要到了并四苯吗
You find a street gang that slings tetracene?
工业打印机墨盒  当年也就14.99美元
Industrial printer cartridge, $14.99 back in the day.
-能给我个支架吗  -给你
- Get me a mount, would you? - Here, here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
你要和上头说
You gonna tell the suits
你在用二十年前的零部件运行它吗
you're running this on a 20-year-old part, right?
我会证明其可行  然后和他们说
I'll show them it works and I'm gonna tell them:
"这就是原型机与
"That's the difference between
量产型号的区别
a prototype and a production model."
好了
Okay.
凹度调整为零
Concavity is spun to zero.
启动镜面追踪
Lens track is hot.
进行直线校准
Alignment is keyed in.
可以开始了
You are good to go.
你来启动吧
I'll let you call it.
如果将其应用于其他材料
If you think about the applications on other materials,
效果会相当明显
it could be fairly significant.
比如说  金属制品
Metals, for instance,
受微小的力或噪音干扰就会被粉碎
can be shattered with very little effort or noise.
混凝土  橡胶...
Concrete, rubber...
在巨大的温差下也会异常脆弱
they're all vulnerable to violent temperature changes.
这个项目是应海豹突击六队之需而启动的
Yeah, this project started as a request from Seal Team 6.
自卢旺达的围城以后
After the siege in Rwanda,
他们就来问我们能否
they came to us asking for the capability to
瞬间冻结或汽化敌人的水源
flash freeze or boil the enemy's water supply.
如今这个装置可以将敌人们赶出来了
Now, this device could have driven the enemy out.
你有在活体上测试过吗
And you... tried this on living things?
这不是我们的初衷
That wasn't our intent here, initially.
希望你们能测试一下
We'd like you test it.
有自愿的吗
Any volunteers?
我们会试试的
Well... we'll give it a try.
先生们  大家先坐下来
Gentlemen, why don't we go have a sit down?
我们谈谈下一步安排  好吗
We'll talk over the next steps. All right?
这边走
Yeah. Right this way.
你是想良心无愧吗
What do you want, a clean conscience?
就算用块牛肉来测试它  我也不在乎
Test it with a slab of beef for all I care.
我只希望不要背离了我们的设计初衷
What I want is to use it for what we originally designed it as.
用于震慑
A deterrent.
没人说过要用来微波加热别人的肺
Nobody said anything about microwaving people's lungs.
这是战争
It's war.
是我们赖以为生的产业
It's the business we're in.
你记得当初雇用我时说的套话吗
Remember what you sold it to me as when you hired me?
致力于防御
Defense.
还是有部分属实的
And that's still partially true.
但战争是桩好生意
But war is good business.
人口贩卖也算
So is human trafficking.
马克  我们效力于国防高级研究计划局
We work for DARPA, Mark.
效力于政府
We work for the government.
"我不知道第三次世界大战会用什么武器
"I don't know what weapons we'll use to fight in World War III,
但第四次世界大战会用..."
but World War IV will be fought with..."
"木棍和石块"  爱因斯坦如是说
"Sticks and stones." said Albert Einstein.
-他也为政府工作  -没错
- He worked for the government. - That's right.
如果你去问他
And if you ask him, I don't think
我想他不会觉得那是他最辉煌的时刻
he thought that was his finest hour.
他肯定也会对把活人瞬间烧糊有意见的
I'm sure he has feelings about flash-boiling human flesh.
想过要研究有全感知反馈的义肢吗
Ever think about prosthetic limbs with full sensory feedback?
研究义肢无助于打胜仗
Prosthetics... don't win wars.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
那是你逐渐失去的作为科学家的同情心
That is the empathetic scientist in you dying.
你和伙计们说了怎么操控射线了吗
Did you brief your guys on how to operate the ray?
-说了  -很好
- I did. - Good.
那你可以开始收拾行李了
Then you can start packing.
能说具体点吗
Can you be more specific?
是关于这些护目镜的
About these goggles here.
你的超光谱护目镜已装备给东欧
Your... hyperspectral goggles being deployed by
摩尔多瓦战役中的特种部队
special forces in eastern Europe in the Moldovan war.
早知道了  我看了现场报告
I'm aware. I read the field reports.
不  你还没看这份报告
No, you have not read this report.
奥伦德亲自打电话给我  奥伦德将军
Orland called me personally. General Orland.
他说那边的情况有点敏感
He said things are very... sensitive down there.
他们见到了些东西
And they're... seeing things.
什么东西
Okay. Like what?
他们不愿意告诉我
They won't tell me.
他们不愿意分享影像内容
They won't share the video feed.
也不愿意讨论所见之物
They won't discuss what they're seeing.
他们只想让首席工程师过去
They just want the lead engineer
提供建议和咨询
down there to advise and consult.
你发明这些护目镜是为了保护我们的人
Look, you invented these goggles to keep our guys safe.
而如今  他们需要你的帮助
Well, now they need your help.
当作是为了防御吧
Think of it as defense.
让我来重启制导系统
Let me reboot the guidance system.
锁得很死  我们要把它拉出来
It's locked tight. We have to pull it out.
摩尔多瓦  东欧
美军空军基地
好了  走吧  移走它
All right, let's go. Move it out.
-马克·克莱恩  -什么
- Mark Clyne? - What?
是你设计的头盔摄像机吗
You the guy that designed the helmet cam?
是的  马克·克莱恩
Yes. Mark clyne.
我是詹姆斯·奥伦德  跟我来
James Orland. Come with me.
这里又来了很多新士兵
A lot of new boots on the ground here.
这个国家一团糟
The country's in chaos.
叛军主要是由军事独裁者余党组成的
The insurgency is mostly remnants of the military dictatorship
直到两个月前他们还控制着该地区
that ran this place until about two months ago.
起初  在国家的北部地区
And their popular support
俄罗斯边境附近
is primarily in the north part of the country,
和首都这里  他们都拥有广泛支持
near the Russian border, and here in the capital.
问题在于他们的军队都训练有素
The problem is their forces are well-trained.
他们威胁要把局势发展成全面内战
They're threatening to turn this whole thing into a civil war.
俄罗斯曾统治摩尔多瓦  后又失去控制
Moldova. Russians had it, lost it.
国家独立了  但内部纷争不断
It became independent, but it's struggling internally.
一方面  是叛军作乱
On the one hand, you have an insurgency,
全都是政府的前精锐部队
made up of the regime's former elite soldiers.
他们全都训练有素且极度危险
They're well-trained and dangerous.
另一方面  这里的大部分国民
On the other, you have most of the population,
都想推翻政府的统治
who are tearing down the regime's flags
渴望新政府
and demanding a new government.
不管有多复杂
Civil unrest, as complicated as it is,
内乱是我们所熟悉的事情
is a business we're familiar with.
我们觉得自己擅长处理内乱
We like to think we're good at it.
但是你的摄像机发现的这个...
But this thing your camera found...
是种全新的玩意儿
It's a whole new piece of business.
我没法把这个视频交给美军欧洲司令部
I can't send this video to EUCOM.
我只是担心他们会认为这是个玩笑
I'm just afraid they'd think it's a joke.
国防部没有幽默感
DOD doesn't have a sense of humor.
通常没有  帮我们装好
Typically not. Hook us up.
我相信这些东西有科学的解释
I'm sure there's a scientific explanation for what's on these,
但是在你告诉我之前
but until you tell me,
我是不会把它上交指挥系统的
I'm not sending it up the chain of command.
-搞定了  -是的  长官
- You done? - Yes, sir.
-出去把我们锁好  在外面等着  -是
- Get out. Seal us in. Wait outside. - Sir.
这里没有人对这个有任何头绪
Nobody here has been able to make heads or tails of this.
由于一些我无法随意告知你的原因
It's thrown a wrench into our entire operation
我们的整个行动都被搅乱了
for reasons I'm not at liberty to discuss with you.
我只能告诉你我们急需解释
I can tell you we need answers fast.
-介意我来吗  -你这么快就看到了
- Do you mind? - You spotted that quick.
五个头盔摄像机
Five different helmet cams
在过去三周内拍到了相似的东西
picked up something similar in the last three weeks.
最初情报技术人员
At first, our signals
认为那是干扰信号
intelligence tech wrote it off as interference.
那可不是干扰信号
That's not interference.
我觉得要是干扰信号的话
I don't think you'd fly me all the way here
不会让我大老远飞到这里来
for interference.
想跟我说说你的想法吗
Wanna tell me what you're thinking?
我想让你先说出你的想法
I want you to tell me what you're thinking.
我...暂时没什么想法
I don't know what I'm thinking... yet.
但这总是有解释的
But there is an explanation.
这是第一次观测到的画面  另外三次类似
That was the first sighting. Three others just like it.
最后一次有些不同
The last was different.
因为牵扯到一位三角洲部队成员
It involved a member of Delta Force,
这让事情变得极其敏感
that makes it particularly sensitive.
这位是中情局的弗兰·麦迪逊
This is Fran Madison with CIA.
这里的特别行动都是中情局的秘密任务
What special ops does here is done under CIA covert operations.
在我们继续之前你得把这个签了
You need to sign this before we go any further.
-这是什么  -敏感信息保证书
- What is this? - It's an SCI oath.
如果你泄露了
You're acknowledging it's life
告诉你的任何事  你将被判终身监禁
in prison if you reveal anything you're told.
敏感信息隔离设施
-找到戴维斯的文件  -是  长官
- Cue up the Davis file, please. - Yes, ma'am.
三天前我们中城区进行了一次突击行动
Three days ago we conducted a raid in mid-city.
我们的通讯时断时续
Our communications were intermittent,
有一位队员与队伍失联了
and a guy got separated from the group...
最终他在行动中被杀
Where he ended up killed in action.
他比任何人离得都近
He got closer than anybody.
太近了
Too close.
这里是D组1队  你们看到了吗
Dagger team 1, you seeing this?
这里有东西在干扰信号
There's some kind of disturbance here.
戴维斯  什么东西  你看到什么了
Davis, what is that? What are you seeing?
见鬼
What the hell?
克里斯·戴维斯中士
Sergeant Chris Davis.
经历过三次战争的老兵  精英中的精英
Three-tour combat vet. Best of the best.
最近几周我们在全城范围内都发现了
In the last few weeks we've been finding bodies around the city
死法相同的尸体
that were killed in the same way.
尸检无法得出结论
The autopsies defied all explanation.
他们的内脏被冰冻住
Their internal organs were frozen
然而皮肤却被烧灼和腐蚀了
and yet, their skin was burned and corroded.
从摩尔多瓦友军方面
The only response from the allied
得到的唯一回应  只有震惊和困惑
Moldovan military contact is shock, confusion.
还有愤怒
And there's anger.
有一些少年
There's teenagers
在出事地点喷涂"灭绝幽魂"的记号
spray-painting "Genocide Aratare" at kill sites.
-灭绝什么  -"幽魂"
- Genocide...? - "Aratare."
当地的传说  战争的鬼魂
It's a local myth. The ghosts of war.
"如同噩梦一般"  大概是这个意思
"As nightmarish as." That's the literal translation.
-还很有诗意  -那是他们的迷信
- That's very poetic. - Well, they're superstitious.
他们不知怎地认为...
They somehow think...
战争的恐怖唤醒了一些非自然的力量
the horrors of the war have kicked up something unnatural.
-我们希望你能给出别的理论  -你怎么看
- We hope you have an alternate theory. - What do you think?
我认为你们得给它们起个新名字
Think you need a new name for them.
除了这个
Beyond that.
给我一份这些数据的拷贝  给我点时间
Give me a copy of the data, some time...
不可能
That's not possible.
你们想让我现在就搞清楚
You want me to figure this out right now?
-我们需要你的看法  -我还没什么看法
- We want your assessment. - I don't have one yet.
那么  我们就得把目前的理论
Then, I think we have to send our working theory
上交给指挥系统
up the chain of command.
我不想这样做
I don't wanna do that.
好吧  目前的理论是什么
Okay. What is your working theory?
我们认为这是一种隐身技术
The agency thinks this is some kind of cloaking technology.
叛军士兵穿着动态伪装服
Insurgent soldiers wearing active camouflage.
在这个国家吗  那么先进的技术
In this country? Something that advanced?
中情局知道欧洲和亚洲的
CIA knows a few groups in Europe
一些组织可能在研究动态伪装服
and Asia could be working on active camouflage.
国防部高级研究计划局也在研究隐形技术
DARPA's worked on cloaking technology.
我们离原型都还差好多年
We're years away from a prototype.
也许有人领先了你们
Maybe somebody beat you to it.
我们已经是这个领域最先进的了
DARPA is the leader in the field.
你确定吗
Are you certain of that?
地方政府斥巨资进行武器研究
The regime spent heavily on weapons research.
腐败  松散的法治
Corruption, loose legislation.
对一个想要低调的军事实验室来说
You're a military lab and want obscurity?
-这里是悄悄进行研究的完美地点  -好吧
- This is a great place to work and hide. - Okay.
我们假设这是一种隐身技术
Let's say it is cloaking technology.
怎么解释死因
How do you account for cause of death?
对受害者的冲击波
A shock delivered to the victim.
我觉得你只是瞎猜的
I think you're reaching.
我们的工作需要进行推测
Our business requires us to make suppositions.
而我的工作需要去证实这些推测
My business requires us to prove them.
你们的技术人员的工作是找到故障
Your technician's job is to find glitches,
所以他们看到了故障
so, he sees glitches.
你们的工作是找到敌人
Your job is to find the enemy,
所以你们看到了敌人
so, you see the enemy.
本地人相信鬼魂  他们就看到了鬼魂
Locals believe in spirits, so they see spirits.
在某一方面  每个人都有自己的偏见
Everyone is biased, in one way or another.
所以  现在我的回答是
So, my answer to you right
我们目前缺少数据来支持任何理论
now is that we lack data to support any theory.
好吧
Okay.
你需要什么来得出更肯定的结论
What do you need to make a more definitive statement?
首先  你们得有更好的画面
First, you need a better shot.
这正是我想要的  更好的画面
That's what I'm looking for, a better shot.
怎么做
How?
-这边  长官  -就是这个
- Right here, sir. - That's it.
我从DARPA带来了这个  超光谱摄像机
I brought this from DARPA. A hyperspectral camera.
比你们用的头盔摄像机更强大的设备
A more powerful version of the helmet cams your guys are using.
它能看到深层次的光谱
It sees deeper into the spectrum of light.
不管是否可见  只要有东西
Visible or invisible, if something's there,
它就能观察到
this'll pick it up.
你能把这东西安在三角洲部队的战车上吗
Can you mount this thing... on a delta vehicle?
-当然可以  -很好
- I don't see why not. - All right, good.
我们每天在城里都有行动
We run missions into the city every day.
我把战地技术人员找来  你教他怎么操作
I'll put you with our field tech, tell him how to operate it.
我不想让我之外的第二个人来操作这部摄像机
I wouldn't put a tech in between this camera and myself.
那你想亲自操作
So, you wanna operate it?
要想拍到关键画面...
If you want that kill shot...
需要快速的临场反应
you'll need a fast reaction time out there.
下次行动  你跟三角洲部队一起
Next mission, you ride with delta.
他们会带你接近那东西
They're gonna get you close to this thing.
等你给我搞到关键画面
You get me the kill shot...
你就可以直接拎包回弗吉尼亚
you can go home to Virginia without unpacking.
有个转子坏了  你得把它换掉
Got a bad rotor, you gotta swap that out.
把它焊在前面板上
Weld it onto the front panel.
瞧瞧这个
Well, well, well. Toll, check that out.
-这家伙在做什么  -我不知道
- What's this guy up to, man? - I don't know.
你相信这家伙吗
Believe this guy?
-如果有作用的话  -说真的
- If it works. - For real.
听说你要在我们的车上装个摄像机
Heard you're installing a camera on our truck.
要是你不把50口径机枪拆下来我本来没意见
Which was fine until you ripped out that 50 Cal.
你拆了把枪换了部摄像机上去
You're taking down a gun to put up a camera?
只有那里有空间放置摄像机
It's the only place large enough to mount it.
你们能明白吧  我知道这听起来像个坏主意
You guys get that, right? I know it sounds like a terrible idea.
我们更喜欢跟带我们的人合作
We prefer to dance with who brung us...
克莱恩博士  懂了吗
Dr. Clyne. You get that, right?
"跟带你们的人合作"  我并不懂
"Dance with who brung you"? No, actually, I don't.
这辆车救过我们的命很多次
This truck has saved our lives, many times.
我明白
I understand.
你们知道这辆车是克莱恩博士的团队制造的吗
You guys know Dr. Clyne's team built that truck?
克莱恩博士在DARPA工作
Clyne works over at DARPA.
我跟他的团队紧密合作过
I've worked closely with his group.
去过他们在弗吉尼亚的设施
Been to their facilities in Virginia.
很高兴见到你  克莱恩博士
Good to see you, Dr. Clyne.
我也是  卡布瑞拉上尉
Good to see you, Captain Cabrera.
他们给这些车改装了更坚固轻便的装甲
They retrofitted these trucks with tougher, lighter weight armor.
他们设计了装载机来搬运重物
They designed the mechanical loaders that do the heavy lifting,
给你们省了力气
so you boys don't strain yourselves too hard.
事实上  克莱恩博士本人
Matter of fact, Dr. Clyne himself
还设计了轻薄的凯夫拉连体紧身衣
developed the thin weight Kevlar body stocking that literally...
来保护你们的蛋蛋
protects your balls.
我希望你们
So, I would think there'd be
都能对克莱恩博士心存感激
nothing but goodwill in this group for Dr. Clyne.
-塞申斯少校  -上尉  让你的人退下
- Major Sessions. - Captain, have your men fall back.
-都散开  -把它放下
- Get back to it. - Get it done.
少校  这位是克莱恩博士
Major, this is Dr. Clyne.
在过去五年他和我们合作过多次
He's worked with us eight or ten times over the last five years.
你要和突击队一起去击杀鬼影吗
You go out with the assault team on hunting ghost?
不  长官
No, sir.
他是个好人  少校
He's a good man, major.
很好  但我不喜欢带游客执行作战任务
That's great. I'm just not a fan of taking tourists on combat missions.
长官  我不是游客
Sir, I'm not a tourist.
如果没携带突击步枪  那你就是个游客
If you're not carrying an M4, you're a tourist.
如果你坚持  我可以配枪
I can carry one, if you'd like.
少校  我们得把克莱恩博士带去战场
Major, we gotta get Dr. Clyne out in the field
这样他才能追踪目标  帮助我们击毙它
so he can track the target force and get us a kill shot.
这个仪器需要多久才能运转
How long before this equipment's operational?
几个小时吧
A few hours.
-会有用吗  -如果我们离得够近
- Is it gonna work? - If we get close enough.
戴维斯中士...就离得够近了
Let me tell you something. Sergeant Davis...he got close enough.
他是我们最顶尖的三角洲队员
That's the best delta that we had.
最好保证你的仪器也是最顶尖的
Make sure your equipment is top-notch this time.
-他们情同手足  -我理解
- They were like brothers. - I get it.
好吧
Okay.
晚上好  博士
Evening, doc.
听说你俩一见如故
Hear you two hit it off bigtime.
-她可以放松一点  -你也是
- She can come off a bit intense. - Yeah. So can you.
我来这儿只是帮你们找到这东西
I'm just here to find this thing.
为了找到它  你都愿意参与作战任务
You're willing to go on a combat mission to find it.
她也是
She is, too.
华盛顿给她施加了太大的压力
She's under a lot of pressure from D.C.
他们想要答案  而她负责找出答案
They want an answer and it's her job to give them one.
在任务名单上看到了你们的名字
Saw your names on a mission roster.
我知道这是最紧要的事
I knew this was a top priority...
但他们把你们俩都派来...
but for them to embed you both...
不用担心我
Well, you don't have to worry about me.
我不担心你  博士  我担心这东西
I'm not worried about you, doc. I'm worried about it.
她认为这是一种隐形技术
She's hoping it's cloaking technology.
你觉得呢
What do you think it is?
我们都还没想到的某种东西
Something no one's thought of yet.
各位  昨天18点
Gentlemen, yesterday at 1800 hours,
U组去杜勒斯地执行侦察任务时
Utah team left here on a recon mission to Durlesti,
与叛军交火了
when they were engaged by insurgents.
我们设法弄清交火时他们说了什么
We managed to hear most of their chatter during the firefight,
但结果并不理想
but comes were unreliable.
目标是这里的一栋五层建筑
Target is a five-story apartment building here.
我们认为活着的U组队员被关押在四楼
We think what's left of utah team is being held on the fourth floor,
位于西北角的房间里
in the northwest corner apartment.
我们将深入叛军占领区域
We're gonna be knee-deep in an insurgent-held area in the city.
所以  做好交战准备
So, we should expect a fight.
最后一件事
One last thing.
我们的人被抓住之前
Before our guys were grabbed,
通过无线电汇报了看到的东西
they radioed in that they saw
我们称之为  超光谱异形物
what we're now calling hyperspectral anomalies.
此次任务要速战速决
Your mission is a quick extraction.
找到U组队员  带他们出来
You get our guys and you get out.
如果交火  将异形物就地消灭
However, if engaged, neutralize the anomalies in the area.
消灭他们
Neutralize them?
-怎么消灭  -我们要对付的是什么
- How? - Yeah, what are we dealing with here?
我们认为是穿着先进电子伪装服的敌方士兵
We believe these are enemy soldiers in advanced electronic camouflage.
所以  交火时务必小心  如果他们...
So, be surgical when you fire. If they are...
如果不清楚他们是什么  也许我们该...
If we don't really know what they are, maybe we should...
不好意思  你想补充什么吗
Excuse me? Would you like to add something?
如果他们穿戴了隐形技术
If they are wearing cloaking technology,
你们要尽可能将其完好无损地带回来
you need to bring it back as intact as possible.
克莱恩博士和麦迪逊特工会和你们一起去
Dr. Clyne and Agent Madison will be on mission with you.
克莱恩博士会在车队中第二辆反伏击车上
Dr. Clyne will be monitoring your helmet-cam feeds
监测你们头盔摄像机的反馈影像
from the second MRAP vehicle in the convoy.
塞申斯少校会带领D组1队进行营救
Major Sessions will lead dagger team 1 to do the extraction.
拿好装备  随时待命
Stay on come. Get your gear.
走吧  伙计
Partner, let's go.
AJ  检查前部和中部
AJ, front and center.
检查武器  比利
Weapons check, Billy.
没问题
You got it.
这路对你来说不够平坦吗
Our ride not smooth enough for you?
你还敢说自己很厉害[屁股坚硬]And you call yourself hard-ass.
他们真应该重新铺一下这条路  兄弟
They really need to repave these roads, man.
好了  伙计们  我们正在进入废弃区
All right, guys, we're coming into the abandoned zone.
做好面对大批叛军的准备吧
Expect a heavy insurgent presence.
慢点
Okay.
我发现了一具叛军的尸体
I've got an insurgent body here.
我发现了U组的高皮  确认阵亡
I got Agopia from Utah team. Confirmed KIA.
他们都没有交火的迹象
None of these guys appear to have taken any rounds.
没有明显外伤
No entry or exit wounds.
阿莱西奥汇报  向五楼移动中
Alessio here. Moving to the fifth floor.
-那边有动静  -托尔  两点钟方向
- We got movement in there. - Toll, check your 2 o'clock.
哪里  我们什么也没看见
Where? We don't see anything.
-没错  就在那儿  -你就在它上方
- That's it. Right there. - You're right on top of it.
有活动迹象  浴缸下有东西
It's a motion signature. There's something under that tub.
路易斯  浴缸  把浴缸翻过来
Lewis, the tub. I want you to flip over the tub.
-托尔  你负责查看下面是什么  -好的
- Toll, I want you on what's underneath. - I'm on it.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
是科姆斯托克  他还活着并且有意识
We have Comstock alive and conscious.
重复  发现U组的科姆斯托克中士
Repeat. We have Sergeant Comstock from Utah team.
伙计
Hey, buddy.
-你们组的其他人呢  -他们在楼上
- Where's the rest of your team? - They're upstairs.
但他们都死了  钻到皮肤下面了
But they're all gone. Got under their skin.
-什么钻到皮肤下面了  -我看到它了
- What got under their skin... ? - I saw it.
-但是...  -毛毯
- But...? - Blanket.
像一条冰冻的毛毯
Like a frozen blanket.
-U组的其他人呢  -他们死了
- Okay, where is the rest of Utah? - Oh, they're dead.
他们都死了
Yeah, they're all dead.
我们都死了
We're all dead.
-尸体在哪  -我说了  在顶楼
- Where are the bodies? - I told you, they're on the top floor.
你还没见过它吧
Oh, you haven't seen it.
我见过了  你知道我信仰上帝  约翰
I've seen it. You know I believe in God, John.
它是上帝的对立面
This is the opposite of god.
等等  这是谁  能让他转个身吗
Wait wait wait. Who's this right there? Can you tell him to turn back?
麦克法登  转过身去
McFadden, turn back.
让我们看看那个房间
Give us a view of that room.
什么也没有  我就站在这儿呢
Nothing's there, guys. I'm standing right here.
麦克  我们正看着它呢
Mac, we're both staring right at it.
就在你视线中央
It's in the middle of your view port.
什么  那个吗  只是个污点而已
What? That? It's a smear.
大概是这破护目镜的问题
Probably these piece-of-shit goggles.
不不不  让他戴上护目镜
No, no, no. Tell him to put them back on.
麦克  把护目镜戴上
Mac, put the goggles back on.
麦克  立刻戴上
Mac, do it now.
-什么情...  -开火
- What the...? - Take the shot.
看到了吗  子弹直接穿过了它
Did you see that? The bullets right through it.
-他射偏了吗  -没射偏
- Did he miss? - He doesn't miss.
塞申斯少校  麦克法登阵亡了
Major Sessions, we have a KIA. McFadden.
超光谱异形物在五楼  西北角
A hyperspectral target is on the fifth floor, northwest corner.
换重型子弹或203s
Switch to heavy rounds or 203s.
无论如何把这东西放倒
Whatever you have to do to bring this thing down.
让他们撤退
Tell your man to pull out.
在那儿
There!
让他们立刻出来
Get everyone out now!
让他们立刻撤退
Tell them to pull out now.
不行  我们不能空手而归
No, no way, we're not leaving empty-handed.
你肯定会空手而归的
I can guarantee you're leaving empty-handed.
快撤
Come on!
手雷
Grenade!
-我们需要支援  -撤退
- We need support! - Get out.
所有队伍立刻撤退  快走  回到车里
All units evacuate now. Let's go. Get back to the truck.
-就在这里  我们还能带上他  -快撤
- This room right here. We can still grab him. - Let's go! Move!
快走  快点
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
快
Go!
这里  这里  吉姆  等等  这里
Here. Here, Jim. Hold on. Here.
从南面撤离
Evacuating via south face!
我和塔尔博特  科姆斯托克
I got Talbot, Comstock,
里德尔还有谢立
Riedel and Shaire.
五人阵亡
Five men down!
我们一起走
We gotta travel together
要跟紧了  你能行吗
and we gotta stay tight. Can you do that?
天啊  走
Oh, Jesus. Go!
快点  快点
Come on. Come on.
让开  让开  让开
Move. Move, move.
扶着他  赶紧走
You got him? Let's go.
给我闪开
Get out of the way.
在哪
Where?
-就在那  -它在哪
- Right there! - Where is it?
前方
In front.
得赶紧上车
We gotta get in.
-把他拉进去  -快点
- Help him in. - Come on!
-快进来  -进去
- Get in here! - In you go.
不
No.
不要
跑  快跑
Go, go!
-跑啊  -上车
- Move! - Get in.
快跑
Go, go!
我们上车了  走吧
We're in! Go!
卡布瑞拉在哪  上尉在哪
Hold on, where's Cabrera? Where's the captain?
说话  你看见他了吗
Talk to me. Did you see him?
-回答我  -我看着他阵亡的
- Come on, talk to me, man. - I saw him die.
-什么  -我看着他阵亡的
- What? - I saw him die.
-我想回家  -没问题
- I'm going home. - Yeah.
-我想回家  -没事的
- I'm going home. - Hey, hey, hey. It's okay.
看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
-你看见它了吗  -是的
- Did you see it? - Yeah.
你看见它了  你离它有多近
You saw it. How close did you get?
我和它共处一室长达几小时
I was in a room with it for hours.
浴缸救了我的命
That tub saved my life.
我能感觉到它的存在
I could feel it.
我能感觉到
有地雷  坐稳了
Land mines! Hold on!
伙计  看着我  别死啊
Hey, buddy, look at me. No, no, no.
该死
Shit.
把门打开
Open the door.
-快走  -来
- Come on. Now, move. - Come on.
两名司机都阵亡了
Both drivers are dead.
呼叫基地  我们遭遇地雷
Archer Lima 2. Hit a land mine.
两辆装甲车都已被炸毁
Both vehicles destroyed.
我们在
We are...
目标建筑的东南方三公里处
three clicks southeast of target building.
我们听不到你们的无线电
We are losing your transmission.
你们的无线电坏了
Your transponders are down.
废话  我们的装甲车都被炸飞了
No shit. Our vehicles were just blown to hell.
我们得找掩体
We need to find cover.
我听不清你说的话
I can't hear what you're saying.
克莱恩  别管摄像机了
Clyne, leave the camera.
快走  克莱恩
Come on, clyne.
快快快
Go, go, go.
快走
Move, move.
掩护
Cover.
-快走  -快起来
- Let's go. - Get up, get up.
走
Come on.
走走走
Go, go, go.
你去哪了
Where you been?
安全
Clear.
谁受伤了
Who's injured?
-迪亚兹  -我脚踝好像受伤了
- Diaz? - I think my ankle's broke.
我们需要空运  但我联系不上基地
We need an airlift. I can't get a signal to base.
继续尝试
Keep trying.
通讯设备给我
Com.
呼叫基地  呼叫基地
Archer Lima 2. Archer Lima 2.
这里是D组1队  收到请回答
This is Dagger team 1, over.
我没事
I'm good. I'm good.
它们能从那里进来吗
Can they get in that way?
你没事吧
You all right?
呼叫基地  这里是D组1队
Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team 1.
收到请回答
Do you copy? Over.
呼叫基地  这里是D组1队  收到请回答
Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team 1. Do you copy? Over.
你怎么样  你在流血
How you doing? You're bleeding.
没事了
Okay.
你撞到头了
You hit your head.
你晕过去了吗
Did you black out?
好像是的
Yeah, I guess so.
少校
Major.
-她的头撞得挺严重的  -我看看
- She hit her head pretty bad. - Let me see.
瞳孔很大
Pupils are huge.
长官  我一直在发信号但他们收不到
Sir, I'm sending but they're not receiving.
我发完后能听到滴答声  但是没有应答
I'm hearing a click back as soon as I sign over, but no answer.
继续尝试
Keep trying.
她吓得不轻  照看好她
She's in shock. Keep an eye on her.
呼叫基地  这里是D组1队  收到请回答
Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team 1. Do you copy? Over.
...去那边
... over there.
其他人呢  U组其他人在哪
Where's everyone else? Where's the rest of Utah?
我是陈中士  我是U组的
I'm Sergeant Chen. I was with Utah.
我们是昨晚第二个来的小组  来了八个
We were the second team in last night. There was eight of us.
你们能确认U组谁已经阵亡了吗
Do you have confirmed KIAs for Utah?
我只能告诉你
Well, I can tell you this much.
科姆斯托克中士今年收不到圣诞贺卡了
Sergeant Comstock's not gonna be on your team Christmas card this year.
-你看到叛军杀了科姆斯托克  -叛军
- You saw insurgents kill Comstock? - Insurgents?
他没毛病吧
Is this guy for real?
-你在哪躲着呢  -我是通讯兵
- What rock were you under? - I was the radio operator.
我们失去联系了  我整晚都被困在卡车里
We lost com. I was stuck in the truck the whole night.
-我没见到动态伪装兵  -动态伪装兵
- I never saw the active camouflage. - Active camouflage?
根本就没有这样的士兵  就算有
Even if there was a such thing, and there's not...
人类怎么可能穿着动态伪装服穿过墙壁呢
How does a human wearing active camouflage walk through walls?
或被三个弹夹的穿甲弹打穿都没死
Or through three mags of armor-piercing ammo?
我看到帕特对其中一个打了至少150发
I saw Pat pump 150 rounds at one of them.
这东西至少杀了19个我们的人
This thing's killed at least 19 of our men.
而我们还不知道它是什么东西
And we have no idea what it is.
克莱恩
Clyne.
你见过它
You saw it.
它是什么东西
What was it?
是人类
Human.
有着人类的外形
Had a human form.
它看着我  有自己的意识
It looked at me, it was conscious.
就像个活人
Like a person.
有什么能解释你看到的东西吗
Is there anything that explains what you saw?
没有
No.
我们把能用的护目镜收集起来
Let's pull together all the functional goggles that we have.
我的护目镜在撞击中坏了
My goggles were wasted in the crash, sir.
我的也是  撞坏了
Yeah. Mine, too. They're trashed.
别管护目镜了  反正我们也没办法充电
Forget the goggles. We can't recharge them anyway.
那我们怎么办
So, what do we do?
我们怎么发现它们
How are we supposed to see them?
也许那台摄像机还能帮上忙
Maybe that camera can still help us.
如果能占领制高点
If we get to an elevated position,
情况可能对我们更有利
we'd have a better vantage point.
来搭把手
Help me with this?
我们走  行动起来
Let's go. Let's move out. Move.
到处都是
They're everywhere.
有什么东西阻挡住了它们
Something's stopping them.
某种黑色沙土
Some sort of black sand.
我在那沙里摔了一跤
I fell in that sand.
-我把它从手里抠出来了  -让我看看
- I had to... pick it out of my hand. - Let me see it.
-一小片尖锐金属  -是铁屑
- Little, sharp pieces of metal. - They're iron filings.
-纯铁  -是啊
- It's pure iron. - Yeah.
一整条铁屑  围绕房子一圈
And there's a trail of it... All the way around the building.
这是一道屏障  有人把它放在那的
It's a barrier. Someone put it there.
看来这里还有人
I don't think we're alone.
整理好装备  我们清理楼上
Let's stack up and sweep upstairs.
瞄准就开枪
Point and shoot?
Point and shoot.
突进  突进
Breach! Breach!
-发现儿童  -安全
- I've got kids. - Clear.
-安全  -解除警报
- Clear. - All clear.
派人守住长墙那里
Tell them to take the long wall.
问他们枪从哪来的  这里还有谁
Ask them where they got this, and who else is here.
问问他们工厂里
Ask them if there's anyone
是否还有其他人  以及他们是否有枪
else in the factory, and do they have guns.
她说只有她们俩在这里
She says they're here alone.
就那一把枪  没有士兵
Only that one gun. No soldiers are here.
-一个人都没有  -塞申斯少校
- No one at all. - Major sessions.
出什么问题了
What's the problem?
这工厂有自己的信号塔
This factory has its own transmission tower.
能发出很强的信号
It puts out a huge signal.
有什么问题吗
So, what's the problem?
32公里内的所有人
Everyone within 20 miles
都能听见我们和基地的通话
will hear our conversation with base.
任何叛军的电台都能截获我们的信号
Any insurgent radio will pick up our transmission.
现在最不用担心的就是叛军
Insurgents are the least of your worries.
尽快和奥伦德将军取得联系
Connect me to General Orland as soon as possible.
呼叫基地  这里是D组
Archer Lima 2, Archer Lima 2, this is Dagger team.
能收到吗
Do you copy?
呼叫基地  这里是D组
Archer Lima 2, Archer Lima 2, this is dagger team.
能收到吗
Do you copy?
呼叫基地  这里是D组
Archer Lima 2, Archer Lima 2, this is dagger team.
能收到吗
Do you copy?
你们是我们的新兵
You guys are our new recruits.
相信我  你们能帮上大忙
And believe me... we could use the help.
来吧  小铁汉  看看你有什么本事
Come on, tough guy. Show me what you got.
我得问你些事儿
Hey, I need to ask you something.
外面的屏障  是你的主意吗
Was it your idea... to put the barrier... outside?
是他们父亲  他们父亲知道
Their father. Their father knew.
他们父亲沿着建筑外围
Their father rolled open barrels of the iron shavings
撒了几桶铁屑
around the building.
他救了他们的命
He saved their lives.
你父亲呢
What happened to your father?
你是个小拳击手是吧
You're a little scrapper, aren't you?
伙计  你没事吧  继续  站起来
Hey, buddy, you all right? Come on, get up.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
你是鬼魂吗
Are you a ghost?
幽魂
Aratare.
他说别说那个词
He says, "Don't say that word."
问他那些东西是什么
Ask him what they are.
失落的灵魂
Lost souls.
死者的灵魂
Souls of the dead.
被困在生与死之间
They're trapped between life and death,
无法安息
and they can't find peace.
为什么会这样
How's that happen?
他说是因为战争
He says, "War."
过来
Come on.
如果是他们的父亲撒下了那些铁屑
If their father was the one who put down the iron shavings,
那他比我们任何人都更了解那些东西
he knows more about these things than any of us do.
问问她父亲在哪儿
Ask her where her father is.
她弟弟波格丹还不知道
Her brother, Bogdan, doesn't know.
他以为父亲只是出去求助了
He thinks he went to get help.
他是在外面弄屏障的时候死的
He died outside, when he was making the barrier.
她只能把他带回这里
She had to bring him in here.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
-我可以吗  -嗯
- Okay? - Yeah.
陶瓷片
Ceramic tile.
问问她父亲是怎么知道
Ask her how her father knew
铁屑能阻挡幽魂的
about the iron filings stopping the Aratare.
他还知道些什么
What else did he know about them?
她什么都不知道
She doesn't know.
马萨罗维
"Masarov."
-马萨罗维是什么  -是一个地名
- What is Masarov? - It's a place.
上游的一个区域
It's a district up the river.
是这一切的源头
It's where it all began.
幽魂杀人就是从那里开始的
It's where the Aratare killings started.
幽魂
Aratare.
要我说就把直升机停这儿
I'm saying we land the helos right here.
我们从这个屋顶撤离  赶紧离开这里
Extract us from this roof and get us the hell out of here.
这里到处都是电话线和电力线
There are phone lines and power lines everywhere.
直升机得飞得又低又慢
The helos would have to fly low and slow.
一个小孩都能扛着火箭筒把它打下来
Easy pickings for a teenager with a shoulder rocket.
少校  现在是什么情况
Major, can you get me up to speed?
和基地联系过了吗
You spoke with base?
联系过了  将军会派直升机来接我们
Yeah. The General's sending in helos to come get us,
以及坦克来确保降落广场周边安全
and tanks to secure the landing zone in an open plaza
距这里约八百米  黎明到达
about half a mile from here, at dawn.
步行的话会很远
That's a long way on foot.
你觉得我们能带着小孩撑过八百米吗
You think we can make it a half mile? With kids?
我们别无选择
We don't have an option. Okay?
所有的路要么被封死要么埋了地雷
All the roads are either blocked or mined.
而且我们用信号塔和基地联系了
And since we used signal tower to talk to base,
所有人都知道我们的位置
everyone knows where we are.
我们得尽快出去
We gotta move out.
那些东西还在街上乱晃
So you wanna go running around out there
你想在这种情况下出去吗
with those things roaming the streets?
我们还没有任何看到和对付它们的办法
Even though we have no way to see or fight?
总比等着它们闯进来要好
Better than waiting for them to find a way in here.
哪里好了
How is it better?
我们没死的唯一原因就是外面的那道屏障
The only reason we're still alive is that barricade out there.
它们迟早会进来的
Look, eventually they're gonna get through.
只是时间问题
It's just a matter of time.
-先消停一下  -我们得冒险一试
- Wait, wait, wait. - We have to take our chances.
-这是目前最好的计划  -少校
- This is the best plan that we have. - Major.
如果我说我能增加成功到达广场的几率呢
What if I told you I can improve our chances of making that plaza?
-你说  -看看周围
- I'm listening. - Take a look around you.
这里到处都是这东西
Everything in this building... is filled with these.
铁屑
Iron dust.
铁能阻止那些超光谱异形
And the iron stops the hyperspectrals.
没错  把它做成武器
Exactly. Weaponize it.
-脏弹  -这是今晚最好的主意
- Dirty bombs. - Best idea I've heard all night.
收集手榴弹
Let's collect the grenades.
克莱恩
Clyne.
在外面我需要你做我们的眼睛
I need you to be our eyes out there.
你能带着摄像机走路吗
Can you haul that camera on foot?
我有更好的主意
I've got a better idea.
这个摄像机本身就能投射相符波长的紫外线
This camera already projects the right wavelength of UV light.
如果我能将它内部翻转过来
If I can turn it inside out,
通过改变一些结构的极性
by reversing the polarity of some of the components,
我也许能把摄像机改造成探照灯
I might be able to turn it from a camera into a searchlight.
我们凭肉眼就能看见它们
We'll be able to see them with our own eyes.
这能大大改善我们的境况
That'd be a game-changer.
我能和基地的车队通话吗
Think I can talk to the convoy?
我或许能告诉它们
I might be albe to tell them
如何对装备做同样的调整
how to do the same with their equipment.
他们过来时也需要能看见它们的设备
When they come get us, they're gonna need eyes, too.
我会帮你联系基地的主工程师
I'll connect you to the main engineer back at base.
收到
Copy that.
他们会在车上装备任何你需要的东西
They're ready to equip their vehicles with whatever you need.
能将需求列表复述一遍给我吗
Can you repeat the whole request back to me, please?
对  没错
Okay, yes. That's correct.
但你需要的是一个
But what you gonna need is a device
能发射短波长光的装置
that emits a very short wavelength of light.
我会详细告诉你怎么改线
I can tell you exactly how to rewire that.
有什么可以装在坦克上的东西吗
Do you have anything you can mount on a tank?
小巷那头有动静
We got movement across the alleyway.
伙计们  有动静  能看看是什么吗
Guys, we got movement. Can we get eyes on it?
麻烦让一下
Hey, guys, stand clear for a second.
车队那边怎么说
What's the word on the convoy?
上次通讯在50分钟以前
Last contact was 50 minutes ago.
他们在前往撤离点的路上
They're on their way to the extraction point.
它们来了  拿好你们的装备
Here they come! Get your gear.
我们15秒后离开这里
We're leaving this building in 15 seconds.
快  我们走
Okay, come on. Let's go.
那是去撤离点最快的路线
That was the fastest way to the extraction point.
她说可以带我们走另一条路
Hey. She says she can show us another way.
塔尔博特  你和克莱恩一起
Talbot, you're with Clyne.
迪亚兹  你领头
Diaz, you're on point.
我们走
Let's go.
没问题  继续走
Yup. Moving.
好  我们走
Okay, let's go.
跟上
Come on.
这边
Come here.
所有人都在
Everybody's accounted for.
-看起来没问题  -我们走  这边
- It looks clear. - Let's move. Come here.
好  她说这里右拐
Okay. She says, "Go right here."
注意  六点钟方向
Hey. Heads up, 6 o'clock.
-快走  -快走
- Move! - Move!
快走
Move!
它们来了
They're coming.
跟上
Come on.
来吧
当心
Watch out!
见鬼
Oh, shit.
快  路易斯  我们走
Come on, Lewis! Let's go!
我觉得起作用了
I think it's working!
-进来  -这边
- In here! - This way.
快走  快走
Move, move.
走
Go!
走啊
-快跟上  -跟上
- Move it! - Come on.
-扶他起来  -起来
- Pick up! - Get up.
-我没事  -走  快走
- I'm good. - Go! Go!
把枪拿稳
Steady your gun!
-趴下  -找掩护
- Get down! - Take cover, man.
快  博士  快点
Come on, Doctor. Come on.
他们来了
Incoming!
一人阵亡  一人阵亡
I got a man down! Man down!
快跑
Run!
-快跑  -那边有更多
- Moving it up! - More on that side!
快点
Hurry.
她说"就在前面  拱门下方"
She says, "Straight ahead, under the archway."
小心点
Watch yourself.
-慢着  -她说就是这里
- Hold it. - She says this is the place.
走  走
Go, go.
应该安全
Looks clear.
-他们在哪里  -快上公交车
- Where are they? - Get on the bus. Go.
救援在哪里
Where's the rescue?
灯光呢
Where's the light?
拜托  亮起来
Come on. Come on, come on. Work. Work. Work.
振作点  没事的
Come on. It's okay.
你确定就是这里吗
You sure this is the place?
-是的  -问他们是否确定
- Yeah. - Ask them if they're sure.
她说"我非常确定"
She said, "I'm pretty sure."
少校
Major.
这玩意坏了  我们没法看到他们
This thing is dead. We can't see them.
看不到了
We're blind.
-是我们的人  -这里就是着陆区
- That's us. - This is the landing zone.
-指挥官  你看到了吗  -那些就是目标
- Commander, are you seeing this? - Those are the targets.
-走  走  走  -快
- Go! Go! Go! - Go!
-走  走  走  -快走
- Go, go, go. - Let's go.
快走
Move. Go on.
向下俯身
On the ground.
开火
Fire.
伏低
Get down!
-听我的命令行动  -前进
- Move on my command. - Move it out!
上方
Overhead!
快到坦克那里  移动到坦克
Let's get to the tanks! Move it to the tanks!
-快走  -走
- Move it! - Move!
走
Move!
-开火  -射击
- Open fire! - Let it go!
-撤回去  -不
- Get back! - No.
撤回去
Get back!
在左边
Left flank!
正后方
Your six!
-他们在哪里  -我不知道
- Where are they? - I don't know!
-波格丹在哪里  -他去哪里了
- Where's Bogdan? - Where'd he go?
-谁和他一起  -你看到他们了吗
- Who's got him? - Do you see them?
我们会找到你的
We'll find you!
-波格丹  -波格丹
- Bogdan! - Bogdan!
带他回来
Get him!
波格丹  波格丹
Bogdan! Bogdan!
-波格丹  -回来
- Bogdan! - Get back here!
回来
Get back here!
-快点  -走吧
- Come on! - Come on.
-扶着她  -起来
- Take her. - Get up.
帮帮她  救救她
Help her! Save her!
我扶住她了
I got her.
我们走
Let's go.
快走
Come on!
-站起来  快  -克莱恩博士  快走
- Get up. Come on. - Dr. Clyne, come on!
-上去  -好了
- Get in! - Okay.
少校  是奥伦德将军
Major. General Orland.
将军  请说
General, go for sessions.
基地已沦陷
Base has been lost!
我们正带你们去避难所
We're sending you to our refugee bunker!
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
我们要去哪里  基地在那边
Hey, where are we going? Base is that way.
-我们不去基地了  -为什么不去
- We're not going to base. - Why not?
基地已被攻陷
It's been compromised.
他们正扩散到街上
Hey, they're spreading through the streets.
到处都是
They're everywhere.
他们就把我们留在这里吗
They just gonna leave us here?
有更多的人要运载
There's more people to airlift.
-这里是什么地方  -入口就在那边
- What is this place? - Entrance is over here.
打开门  打开门
Open the door! Open the door!
退后
Get back!
放下你们的武器
Put your weapons down.
放下你们的武器  立刻放下
Put your weapons down! Do it now!
他说"里面安全"
He's saying, "Safe inside."
没事了  没事了
Okay. It's okay.
跟紧
Stay close.
看着我  看着我
Hey, hey, hey. Look at me. Look at me.
她不怎么好  过来
She's not okay. Come here.
需要找个地方  没事的  没事的
I'm gonna need some room. It's okay. It's okay.
基地究竟出什么事了
What the hell happened to base?
基地被攻陷了
Base got overrun.
将军会在这里跟我们见面
The general is meeting us here.
这是什么地方
So, what is this place?
我们在民用的避难所
We're in a civilian refugee shelter.
这避难所有六米厚的钢筋混凝土
This bunker has 20 feet of concrete and steel.
我不知道在这里是否安全  但有食物和水
Are we safe here? I have no idea. But there's food and water.
塔尔博特  尽可能收集物资
Talbot, gather what you can.
托尔  陈  回到入口处
Toll, chen, head back to the entrance.
那里有通讯中心  看能联络到谁
There's a com center. See who you can reach.
阿莱西奥  你和我一起  走吧
Alessio, you're with me. Let's go.
-那边  -哪里
- There. - Where?
-那边  -就在那里
- There. - Right over there.
-好的  -放到床上
- Okay. - On the bed.
没事的  你会没事的
You're okay. Shh. You're gonna be okay.
-怎么了  -是她的肩膀
- What happened? - It's her shoulder.
-她的肩膀里有弹片
- Her shoulder has shrapnel in it.
-我们要剪开衣袖
- We're gonna cut open her sleeve.
准备静脉输液管
Get the IV line ready.
这是你的
This is yours.
莎莉  我现在需要你帮忙  为了阻止幽魂
Now, I need your help, Sari, to stop the aratare.
我必须知道你爸爸所知道的
I need to know what your father knew.
你爸爸是做什么的
What did your father do?
他是制陶的
He worked with ceramics.
他制作些什么呢
What did he make?
他制造容器
He made containers.
他为马萨罗维制造容器
He made containers for Masarov.
幽魂就是来自那里的发电厂
The power plant where the aratare came from.
让她带上氧气面罩
Let's get the mask on her.
现在她得交给我们了
Okay, we have to take her now.
-我们是美国军队  -开门
- This is the U.S. armed forces! - Open it.
放下武器
Lower your weapons.
-你们有多少人  -不怎么多
- How many are you? - Not many.
帮一下他们
Let's give them a hand.
走吧
Let's go.
尽可能多带点
Bring as much as you can.
基地被攻陷了
The base was overrun.
那东西就像一道波浪
It was like a wave.
隐形的波浪
Invisible.
大家就开始倒下
Men just started falling.
我们的常规武器毫无作用
Our conventional weapons were useless.
我请求下令撤离基地...
I requested an order to evacuate the base...
但远距离通讯系统完全被扰乱
But our long-range come are completely scrambled.
所以我把能带的装备都带上
So, I took all the gear I could.
开始让各小队向北撤离行动区
I started sending units north out of the area of operation.
让五架飞机保持最小耗燃量
Kept five aircraft with the least amount of fuel,
跟着一个排殿后
stayed behind with one platoon.
我们240人只剩下19个了
Out of the 240 of us, we have 19 remaining.
有成功向上级通报吗
Did you get a message to higher command?
没有
No.
有安排救援计划吗
Is there a rescue mission planned?
没有  我们截取了
No. We intercepted radio chatter
摩尔多瓦友方无线电信号才找到这里
from Moldovan friendlies to find this place.
我们派出直升机接你们过来
We sent that bird to pick you up and bring you here.
你们要是试着回基地  就已经没命了
If you'd even tried to return to base, you'd be dead.
我们是这个国家最后的美军吗
We're the last U.S. Forces in the country?
但愿如此
I hope so.
有什么计划吗  长官
So, what's the plan, sir?
来这里重新部署  少校
Came here to regroup, Major.
没什么计划
There's no plan.
-我建议加固入口  -用什么加固
- I recommend we fortify the entrance. - Fortify with what?
-我们等待救援...  -用什么加固
- We wait till a rescue mission... - Fortify with what?
无论你用什么东西  他们都能穿过
They'll come through whatever you use.
我们得用直升机碰一碰运气...
We need to take our chances get on one of our helos...
只能飞二十分钟
Twenty minutes of flight time!
直升机只剩二十分钟的飞行时间了
There's twenty minutes of flight time in those birds.
飞不了更久了
Not more!
没关系  反正也装不下所有人
Doesn't matter, there's not enough room for all of us...
我们得组队乘飞机
We need to form teams and take the aircraft.
但你要去哪里  少校
But where you gonna go, Major?
你们躲不掉它们
You can't run from them.
你们无法阻止它们  你们的武器毫无作用
You can't stop them. Your weapons are useless.
我们不知道它们到底是什么
We have no idea what they are!
要是它们穿门而入  我们只能坐以待毙
If they come through that door, we're sitting ducks.
我们阻止不了它们  我们阻止不了它们
We can't stop them! We can't stop them!
把我们能带走的都带走
Take what we can and go.
我知道它们是什么了
I know what they are.
我们觉得我们见鬼了
We think we're seeing things.
我们觉得它不是真的  但它有杀伤力
We think it can't be real, but it kills.
所以它是真的
So, it is real.
是一种物质
It's something.
非光非影
It's not light, it's not shadow,
不是幻觉  可以穿墙  没错
or some trick of the mind. Pass through walls, check.
属于非可见光谱  没错
Outside the visible spectrum, check.
一触即死  没错
Kills to the touch, check.
科姆斯托克当时躲在瓷浴缸底下  对吧
Comstock. He was under a ceramic bathtub, is that right?
坦克装甲  它不能穿过坦克装甲
Tank armor. It couldn't pass through tank armor.
M1艾布兰主战坦克装甲周身镀瓷
M1 Abrams tank armor, that's ceramic plating everywhere.
它不能穿过瓷制品
It cannot pass through ceramic.
你们知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
意味着这东西不是天然的
It means this stuff isn't natural.
有人创造了它
Someone made it.
它是人造的
It's man-made.
怎么人造的
Man-made how?
世上有固体  液体  气体
Okay. You have solid, liquid, gas.
熔岩可以凝固成岩石
Lava can turn into rock.
冰可以融化成水
Ice can turn into water.
金属能熔化  这些都是自然状态
Metals can melt. These are natural states.
但也有非自然状态
But there are unnatural states.
人造状态  人创造的状态
Artificial states, man-made states.
凝聚态
Condensate.
玻色-爱因斯坦凝聚态
Bose-Einstein condensate.
一种由奈斯·玻色
A state of matter that was
和阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦预测的一种物质状态
predicted by Nath Bose and Albert Einstein.
它有一些非常反常的特性
It has some very unusual properties.
会被铁屑减速
It can be slowed down by iron filings.
它不能穿过瓷制品  但却可以穿墙
It cannot pass through ceramic, but it can pass through walls.
温度太低以致于一触即死
It's so cold it will kill you instantly on contact.
它可以解释我们所见的一切
It can do everything we've been seeing here.
要想产生波色-爱因斯坦凝聚态
You want to create Bose-Einstein condensate.
你们需要能量  大量的能量
You need power, and you need a lot of it.
马萨罗维  那个核电站
Masarov. The power plant.
对  马萨罗维  它们的制造地
Yes, Masarov. Where they were made.
你说这个国家在武器研究上投资数十亿
You said this country was pouring billions into weapons research.
这就是武器
This is a weapon.
这要么是有意释放  要么是意外爆发
And it was set loose, or it broke loose.
好吧  但这些东西会爬
All right, but these things climb.
它们就像人类  看起来像人一样
They're like human beings. It looks like a person.
大理石和泥土也能塑成人型
So can marble and clay in the right hands.
我想知道为什么
And I wanna know why.
它们为什么看起来像人
Why they look like people.
我不知道它们是怎么做的
I can't tell you how they did this.
我只能告诉你它们是人造的
What I can tell you... is that someone made them.
如果是人造的
If someone made them,
它们就逃不开世界的规律
they don't escape the laws of the world.
没有东西能逃开
Nothing does.
它适用于我们需要了解的新规律
It shines light on new laws, and that's what we have to learn.
因为它们有序有结构
Cause they have order and structure.
它们就可以被瓦解
They can be broken down.
任何东西都可以被瓦解  全看所需的能量
Anything can be broken down. It's just energy.
因为我已经知道了它们是什么
And cause I know what they are,
知道了特性  我就可以造出对应的武器
I know the properties, I can build the right weapons.
什么样的武器
What kind of weapons look like?
等离子放电枪  它们可以瓦解凝聚态
Plasmic-discharge weapons. They can tear apart the condensate.
你让我们上哪里找那种武器
Where do you expect that we can find weapons like that?
我们不找  我们自己造
We're not gonna find them, we're gonna build them.
用什么造
Build them with what?
能在掩体里找到的所有东西
Anything we can find in this bunker.
所有电子学  光学和弹道学的部件
Anything with electronics, optics, ballistic casings.
所有从基地带来的零件
All the gear you brought from base.
我们可以全部拆开  我来造一个军火库
We can take it all apart, and I can build an arsenal.
接着我们可以去马萨罗维
And then we can go to Masarov
在事态进一步恶化前阻止它
and we can stop this before it goes any further.
因为如果我们不去
Because if we don't,
一路汲取所有能量的凝聚态
the condensate which feed on all the energy in its path
会呈指数型增长
will grow exponentially.
传播的范围将难以估量
There's no limit to how far they can spread,
除非我们阻止它们
unless we stop them.
伙计们  把零件拖进去  加把劲
Let's get this gear inside, guys. Come on.
行动
Let's move!
每边的数字一样
Same number each side.
好了  动起来  兄弟们
All right, let's go, boys!
有MED部件吗
Any med patches in there?
我在这找到三个
We got three of them over here.
这是地对空追踪瞄准镜
It's a ground-to-air tracking scope.
我们可以用这个  它们光学性能很好
We can use this. They have good optics.
-好的  这很好  -这边还有两个
- Good. This is good. - Two more over there.
看到那个305了吗
See that 305?
半数被贴上了"残次品"标签
Half of these are labeled "Defective."
我们需要一个反向电压
We're gonna need a voltage counter.
你们现在就开始测试这些东西
I want you to start testing these.
好了  打开
All right, open it up.
打开  掀开
Get that one open. Pop it.
和我想的一样吗
Is that what I think it is?
我们从基地拿来的路特斯
We got the Lotus from base.
太厉害了
That's badass.
-像一只机械罗特韦尔犬  -看啊
- Looks like a mechanical rottweiler. - Look at that.
克莱恩做了些调整
Clyne's making a few changes.
他们在卸下链式起重机  装上探照灯
They're taking down a chain hoist and putting up a searchlight.
似曾相识嘛
Déjà vu.
-它发射什么  -一种聚焦能量脉冲
- What does it fire? - It's a focused energy pulse.
如果我没算错的话
If my math is right...
它应该可以瓦解凝聚态
it should break down condensate.
马萨罗维
Masarov.
本地区唯一的最大的核电站
The single largest power plant in the region.
也是死亡的发源地
It's where the killings started.
如果它们是人造的  那一定就是在这里
If they're man-made, they were made here.
距离这里不到十公里
It's less than ten klicks from here.
飞机可以到达  但可能只有一条路
Our birds can make that, but... it's probably one way.
我一直在当地居民那里挖掘线索
I've been digging for clues with the civilians here.
我找到了关于马萨罗维的情报
I found this intel on Masarov.
在过去十年间  它被中央政权
It's been retrofitted several times over the last decade
翻新过很多次
by the central regime.
表面写满了"武器研究"的字样
It's got "Weapons research" written all over it.
好的  你和克莱恩需要潜进去
Okay, you and Clyne need to be embedded to infiltrate.
就指望你们弄清楚怎么停止这一切了
It's gonna be up to the both of you to figure out how to stop this.
我们得声东击西
We have to create a diversion.
我们会在这里吸引它们好让你们潜入内部
We'll draw them out here so you can infiltrate the structure
试着找到源头
and try to find the source.
克莱恩说这些武器会释放高温电流
Clyne's predicting the charge from these weapons will be extremely hot.
足够摧毁凝聚态
Enough to destroy condensate.
我们很快就可以验证一下了
We'll find out soon enough.
好了  兄弟们
All right, boys.
就这样了
This is it.
如果还有什么遗言
If you have any last words...
现在说吧
now's the time.
好  听好了
All right, listen up.
你们用的是未经测试的武器
You are using untested weapons...
抵抗此刻看来是无法被击退的敌人
against an enemy that, to this point, has been unstoppable.
现在你们要前往未知的领地
Now, you are heading into unknown territory.
听清楚了
And hear me when I say
你们会看到一些无法理解的东西
you're gonna see things you will not understand.
我们的敌人已在数日之内遍布全城
Our enemy has spread through the city in a matter of days.
不知道它们会传播多远
There's no telling how far they will spread...
除非我们反击
unless we fight back.
很多人都不曾有机会改变未来
Most men never even come close... to changing the future.
此地
This is the place.
此刻
And now is the time.
毫无疑问  你们是最后一道防线
Make no mistake, you're the last line of defense.
让我们完成最初的使命
Let's go do what we came here to do.
出发  出发
Let's go, let's go!
一分钟
One minute.
三十秒
Thirty seconds.
先锋一号  准备下降
Spearhead 1, proceed with descent.
好了  出发
All right, let's go.
我们走
Here we go.
行动
Let's move!
发现目标
We have a visual.
敌方目标聚集在12点方向平台东端
Hostile target gathering at 12 o'clock on east end of platform.
行动
Move, move!
可以射击
We are a go.
确认杀死一只幽魂
I have a confirmed spectral kill.
可以行动  重复  全体行动
We're a go. I say again, all units go.
-让它们看看我们的厉害  -走
- Let's show them what we've got. - Come on.
-成败在此一举了  -上吧
- This is it! - Let's do it!
我们上  降落
Let's go. Drop.
收到  先锋一队  全体进攻
Copy, Spearhead 1. All units engage.
先锋二队控制北半岛
Spearhead 2 taking north peninsula.
先锋三队开始进攻南半岛
Spearhead 3 beginning descent over south peninsula.
至少出现了一打目标
At least a dozen targets coming out.
-进攻  -我们行动
- Go! Go! - Let's move!
-听我命令  -全体人员  允许进攻
- On me! - All units, you are clear to engage.
-进攻  -进攻
- Move in! - Move it!
目标锁定  准备射击
Lock and load.
-出击  -我们行动
- Move out. - Let's move.
在你身后
Right behind you!
允许开火  允许开火
Weapons free! Weapons free!
我们走  冲啊
Let's go. Move up!
-冲啊  -快
- Move! - Come on!
-进攻进攻进攻  -进攻
- I said go, go, go! - Move!
先锋二队  目标内部设施  前往渗入点
Spearhead 2, you're go for infield. Proceed to insertion point.
走走走
Go, go, go!
趴下
Get down!
就在那
Right there.
-托尔  -快跑
- Toll! - Go! Go!
快跑
Go, go, go!
-谁去控制高点  -下面出现目标
- Somebody get on top! - Down right there!
-更多目标出现  -保持队形
- We got more incoming! - Keep formation!
前进
Let's move it!
进攻  进攻
Fight! Fight!
进攻
Move!
-进攻进攻进攻  -冲啊  约翰
- Let's go, go, go! - Go, John!
-有情况报告吗  -马上
- Do we have a sit-rep? - Right now.
克莱恩  下面情况如何
Clyne, what's the situation down there?
塞申斯  我们被分开了
Sessions, we got split up.
还在寻找实验室
We're still looking for the lab.
我们还在撑着  不知道能撑多久
We're holding. Don't know how long.
-收到了吗  -能听到吗  塞申斯
- Do you copy? - Can you hear me? Sessions?
我们得继续前进
We gotta keep going.
肯定很近了
We gotta be close now.
天哪
God.
看这里
Look over here.
波色-爱因斯坦凝聚态
Bose-Einstein condensate.
看那些X光线
Look at these x-rays.
他们在扫描人类  而且是分子级别的
They were scanning people. On a molecular level.
然后用凝聚态打印出来
And printing them out of condensate.
这是条装配线
It's an assembly line.
就像某种...
Like some kind of...
工业生产线
Industrial process.
没错
You're right.
这就是个武器
It's a weapon.
这里发生了什么
What happened here?
看起来像是出现了灾难性故障
It looks like a catastrophic failure.
一半单元格破损而且已经空了
Half the cells are broken and empty.
肯定是结构损坏让它们逃了出来
Some structural failure must have set them free.
打开了潘多拉魔盒
Opened up pandora's box.
现在怎么办
Now what?
敌人出现
Incoming!
12点钟方向
Hey, 12 o'clock!
-开枪  -它起来了  它们又聚合了
- Do it! - It's up! They're coming back together!
-要来了  -瞄准目标
- They're moving! - All eyes on target.
-有一个重新聚合了  -干掉它
- One of them is reforming. - Bring it down!
中央政府高端研究顾问
"Top research advisers of the central regime."
他想要阻止这个局面的  确实是失控了
This man was trying to stop it. They did lose control.
你能翻译这个吗
Can you translate this?
是紧急关闭程序
It's an emergency shutdown procedure.
上面一半的字我都没见过
Half these words I've never seen.
另一半写的什么
What about the other half?
解耦  解耦程序
"Decouple... decouple procedure.
断开脐带链接
Disconnect the umbilicals to,
以中断神经活动
uh... interrupt the... neural activity."
-好的  -所以你得解锁所有端口
- Okay. - So, you gotta unlock all these ports.
然后拉这个
And then you gotta pull
操纵杆  断开所有电缆
this bracket here to release all the cables.
然后呢
And then?
应该就能阻止它们了
That should stop them.
拿着
Take this.
快点  给我起来
Come on! Get up!
在那里  又增加了
Right there! There's more!
又出现一个
Another one!
就在那
Got it right there!
-克莱恩  -我知道
- Clyne! - I know!
搞什么
What the hell?
我都断开了  没有用啊
I did them all. Nothing's happening.
克莱恩  拉操纵杆  中间那个
Clyne! Pull the bracket! In the middle!
-不  -不
- No! - No!
-结束了吗  -不知道
- Is it over? - I don't know.
你还能走路吗
Can you walk?
-我没事  -来吧
- I'm all right. - Come on.
我们得找条出路
We have to find a way out.
-听到了吗  -听到了
- Do you hear that? - Yeah.
是这里了
This is it.
他们不只是扫描人类
They weren't just scanning people.
它们也不仅仅是打印物
They're not just printouts.
这是控制他们的东西
This is what's controlling them.
这些是真正的尸体
These are from real corpses.
每一个都是一条生命
Each one is made from a real person.
他们都还活着吗
They're alive?
并非活着
They're not alive.
但也没有死亡
They're not dead.
他们被困在了生死之间
They're just trapped somewhere in between.
但是十分痛苦
But they are in pain.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
这就是痛苦
This is pain.
那你怎么知道他们能感觉到
But how do you know they can feel?
我无法证明
I can't prove it.
确实
I can't.
也许科学确实无法回答一切问题
So, maybe there are things science can't answer.
不
No.
等等  不要
Wait, no.
这是我们来这里的目的
This is why we came here.
这都是证据  是你来的目的  记得吗
This is the evidence. This is why you came, remember?
记得吗  已经死了那么多人  你说的
Remember? So many people have died. You said it.
-你说你要知道原因  -已经够了
- You said, "I wanna know why." - I know enough.
你得为大局考虑
You have to think about the bigger picture.
这就是为大局
I am.
帮他们依次下机
Help them off single file.
后续还有更多伤员
Got more coming in!
送他们去第五小队
Put them in unit 5.
-这边这边  -小心他的脖子
- Over here. Over here. - Watch his neck.
我没事
Yeah. Yeah, I'm okay.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
这边  先生
Right there, sir.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
你没事吧
You okay?
来了新调查队
New survey teams.
他们要把马萨罗维拆成碎片
They're gonna take Masarov apart piece by piece.
测量一切
Measure everything.
试图重新建造
Try to reverse-engineer it.
争夺所有权
Fight over ownership.
他们要我问你
I've been asked if you wanna
愿不愿意参加  我答应了  但是
go back out there. I said I'd ask, but...
我来的目的已经达到了
I've seen what I came to see.
他们真是永不停息啊
They don't stop, do they?
我想恐怕他们是不会
I don't think they know how.
跟你说了你可以直接拎包回弗吉尼亚
I told you you'd go home to Virginia without unpacking.
三角洲小队  出发
Delta unit, move out.
谢谢
Thank you.